{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Fasten your seatbelts. It's going to be a bumpy night.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"We'll always have Paris.\"","\"I'm as mad as hell, and I'm not going to take this anymore!\"","\"I'll be back.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'All About Eve'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Elizabeth I","incorrectAnswers":["Mary I","Victoria","Elizabeth II"],"question":"Which English Queen is the US State of Virginia named after?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Melon ","incorrectAnswers":["Cucumber","Peach","Pineapple"],"question":"What Kind Of Fruit Is A Canteloupe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Slovenia","Greece"],"question":"Graz is a city in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Asia","North America","Oceania"],"question":"Where is the world's largest desert?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Gustave Flaubert","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Vicomte of Bragelonne: Ten Years Later'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lena River","incorrectAnswers":["Ob River","Yenisei River","Volga River"],"question":"What is the name of the longest river in Russia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Euclid","Wilhelm Conrad Roentgen","Mencius"],"question":"Which influential historical person was a key figure of the European Enlightenment whose satirical writings played a role in the French Revolution?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Whiplash","incorrectAnswers":["Full Metal Jacket","Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri","Aladdin"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A drummer is mentored by an instructor who will stop at nothing to realize a student's potential.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Olive","incorrectAnswers":["Lemon","Lime","Anchovy"],"question":"What type of brine is added to a traditional dirty martini?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pelmeni","incorrectAnswers":["Larb","Biryani","Khachapuri"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Russia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"99 Luftballoons","incorrectAnswers":["Bust a Move","Nothing Compares 2 U","I'Ve Never Been to Me"],"question":"What song did Nena have a hit with in 1984?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo & Juliette","Hamlet","King Lear"],"question":"Double, double toil and trouble, Fire burn, and cauldron bubble. Comes from which of Shakespeare's plays?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the song 'Paradise'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Bram Stoker","incorrectAnswers":["Mary Shelley","Edgar Allen Poe","Jane Austen"],"question":"Who was the author of Dracula?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Julius","incorrectAnswers":["Augustus","Nero","Trajan"],"question":"Which Roman statesman and military general was assassinated in 44 BC?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"living tissues","incorrectAnswers":["angels","prehistoric environments by analyzing fossils and rock strata","intonation in speech"],"question":"What is Histology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Jamaica","Venezuela"],"question":"In which country is the city of Cordoba?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belize","incorrectAnswers":["Chile","Algeria","Central African Republic"],"question":"Belmopan is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'A Saucerful of Secrets'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Fat Bottomed Girls'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Nile","incorrectAnswers":["The Amazon","The Congo","The Zambezi"],"question":"Which river is joined by the Atbarah River in northern Sudan as its last tributary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Washington","incorrectAnswers":["Oregon","Texas","Wyoming"],"question":"Which US state is often nicknamed 'The Evergreen State'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Juliet","incorrectAnswers":["Hamlet","Ophelia","Polonius"],"question":"Which of the following is NOT a character in Shakespeare's play 'Hamlet'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pound","incorrectAnswers":["Euro","Dollar","Shilling"],"question":"What is the name of the British currency?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Soccer","incorrectAnswers":["Baseball","Basketball","Hockey"],"question":"In the 1992 film \"Ladybugs\", a flustered Rodney Dangerfield coached a girls' team in which sport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Celsius","incorrectAnswers":["Fahrenheit","Kelvin","Rankine"],"question":"On which scale is normal human body temperature approximately 37 degrees?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"IBM","incorrectAnswers":["Electronic Arts","IMAX","FedEx"],"question":"'Solutions for a smart planet' is a slogan associated with which technology brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J.D. Salinger","incorrectAnswers":["James Heller","Arthur B. Miller","Kurt Vonnegut "],"question":"Who wrote The Catcher in the Rye?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lake Baikal","incorrectAnswers":["Lake Superior","Lake Victoria","Loch Ness"],"question":"What is the world's deepest lake?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brunei","incorrectAnswers":["Haiti","Benin","Bhutan"],"question":"Bandar Seri Begawan is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which Swedish pop group released the album 'Ring Ring'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Venus","incorrectAnswers":["Neptune","Mars","Jupiter"],"question":"Which planet in the solar system comes the closest to Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bon Jovi","incorrectAnswers":["Incubus","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which rock band from the United States released the studio album 'These Days'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the song 'Poker Face'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Don McLean","incorrectAnswers":["Elvis Presley","Prince","Cliff Richard"],"question":"Who was the song 'Killing Me Softly' written about?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sting","incorrectAnswers":["Bono","Edge","Adam Clayton"],"question":"Which musician is not part of the band U2?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Manual Labor","incorrectAnswers":["Coal-Powered Machines","Steam-Powered Machines","Solar-Powered Machines"],"question":"What was the primary source of power for the majority of people in the 17th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Grenada is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangladesh","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Thailand"],"question":"Which of these countries borders India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A skulk","incorrectAnswers":["A school","A yoke","A stud"],"question":"What is the word for a group of foxes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Smallpox","incorrectAnswers":["Anthrax","Coronavirus","Measles"],"question":"The world was declared safe from which virus in 1979?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Moses","incorrectAnswers":["Abraham","Isaac","Jacob"],"question":"In the Abrahamic scriptures, who asked Pharaoh to let his people go?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Iran","incorrectAnswers":["North Africa","Vietnam","Italy"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Chelo Kebab?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aswad","incorrectAnswers":["Abrah","Salar","Jawab"],"question":"Which pop group took their name from the Arabic word for black?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Rice Burroughs","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Barsoom'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marathon Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Graduate","Rain Man","Tootsie"],"question":"In which 1970's films does Dustin Hoffman play the character ' Babe Levy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kate Winslet","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Kirsten Dunst","Sandra Bæ Hovedr"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in films including Titanic and The Reader?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Confederacy of Dunces","incorrectAnswers":["Tinker","All the King's Men","We Have Always Lived in the Castle"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Ignatius Reilly'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Tiercel","incorrectAnswers":["A Jack","A Cob","A Boar"],"question":"What is a male falcon known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"All Along the Watchtower\" by Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"Chimpan-A to Chimpan-Z\" by Troy McClure","\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"There must be some kinda way out of here / Said the joker to the thief...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Yemen","Japan","Vietnam"],"question":"In which country would you find the Abu Simbel temples?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Anaxagoras","incorrectAnswers":["Denis Diderot","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'In everything, there is a share of everything'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Goldfinger","incorrectAnswers":["Casino Royale","Spectre","Dr. No"],"question":"Which James Bond theme song was performed by Shirley Bassey?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Israel","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Brazil","Egypt"],"question":"In which country would you find the City of Jerusalem?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Kiwi","Banana","Cherry"],"question":"Which of these fruits is a pome?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Yen","incorrectAnswers":["Dollar","Dong","Yuan"],"question":"What is the currency of Japan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ethelred","incorrectAnswers":["Alfred","Ethelstan","Edward"],"question":"In the period 978-1016 England was ruled by which 'Unready' King?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Glam","incorrectAnswers":["Grunge","Hippie","Preppy"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion trend popularized in the 1980s that involves wearing neon colors, spandex and leg warmers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["Belize","Guatemala","Cuba"],"question":"Which of these countries borders United States of America?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Of Mice and Men","incorrectAnswers":["Master and Commander","We Have Always Lived in the Castle","The Moviegoer"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Lennie Small'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Kurt Vonnegut","Thomas Hardy","Ernest Rutherford"],"question":"Who wrote the book \"The Origin of Species\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fugees","incorrectAnswers":["Run D.M.C","Black Eyed Peas","Poison"],"question":"Which Band Consisted Of The Following Members “Wyclef Jean, Lauryn Hill, Pras Michel\"? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cuba Gooding, Jr.","incorrectAnswers":["William H. Macy","Armin Mueller-Stahl","Edward Norton"],"question":"Who won the 1996 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Rod Tidwell in Jerry Maguire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Renault","incorrectAnswers":["Porsche","Rolls-Royce","Land Rover"],"question":"The Clio is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Rhine ","incorrectAnswers":["Bavaria","The Black Forest","Brandenburg"],"question":"From what German region do Hock wines come?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catherine Of Aragon","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Boleyn","Anne Howard","Catherine Parr"],"question":"Who Was The 1st wife of henry VIII? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Culture Club","Dire Straits"],"question":"Which English-Australian pop group released the studio album 'Idea'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Drone","A Tiercel","A Jack"],"question":"What would you call a male hippopotamus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Lamb ","incorrectAnswers":["Beef","Pork","Chicken"],"question":"Traditionally what type of meat is used to make a mousakka?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rattlesnakes","incorrectAnswers":["Spiders","Frogs","Beetles"],"question":"__________ gather in groups to sleep through the winter. ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Oilers","incorrectAnswers":["Broncos","Seahawks","Bruins"],"question":"Hockey: The Edmonton __________.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Feathers","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Eggs","Beaks"],"question":"What makes an animal a bird?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Walter Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","J. R. R. Tolkien","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Ivanhoe'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kiribati","incorrectAnswers":["Oman","Barbados","El Salvador"],"question":"Tarawa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gothic","incorrectAnswers":["Grunge","Hippie","Preppy"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion trend popularized in the 1990s that involves wearing dark colours, plaid shirts, Doc Martens, and ripped jeans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Eustachian tube","incorrectAnswers":["Philtrum","Maxillary bulb","Optic nerve"],"question":"What connects the nose to the ear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Amazon ","incorrectAnswers":["The Missouri","The Mississippi","The Rio Grande"],"question":"What's the longest river in the Americas?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hathor","incorrectAnswers":["Isis","Set","Horus"],"question":"Who was the ancient Egyptian goddess of the sky and queen of heaven ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Right Said Fred","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Our Lady Peace","Feeder"],"question":"Who Had A Hit In 1994 With \"Wonderman\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gladiators","incorrectAnswers":["Knights","Ninjas","Beserkers"],"question":"Which fighters began a bout by saying, 'Hail Emperor, those about to die salute you'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A school","incorrectAnswers":["A parliament","A field","A charm"],"question":"What is the word for a group of porpoises?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple ","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Peach","Apricot"],"question":"Which fruit has the scientific name of malus pumulia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Chicago","incorrectAnswers":["Denver","Dallas","Seattle"],"question":"The St. Valentine's Day massacre took place in this which city? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Sailing","incorrectAnswers":["Golf","Motorsports","Horse Racing"],"question":"What sport would you associate with The Americas Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Thee","incorrectAnswers":["Himself","His mother","The moon"],"question":"In sonnet 18, who is Shakespeare comparing to a summer's day?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Opium War","incorrectAnswers":["The Hong Kong War","The Mandarin War","The Boxer Rebellion"],"question":"How was the 1839-42 Anglo-Chinese war better known ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frances McDormand","incorrectAnswers":["Viola Davis","Andra Day","Vanessa Kirby"],"question":"Who won the 2020 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Fern in Nomadland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas fils","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Albert Camus","Gustave Flaubert"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Lady of the Camellias'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"5","incorrectAnswers":["1","0","3"],"question":"How many hearts do earthworms have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","American Football","Soccer"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Masters?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Stallion","A Ram","A Boar"],"question":"What is a male kangaroo known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rome","incorrectAnswers":["Athens","Paris","London"],"question":"The Colosseum is an iconic structure in what city?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lewis Carrol","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","T. S. Elliot","Thomas Hardy"],"question":"What was the pen name of author Charles Lutwidge Dodgson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sandra Bullock","incorrectAnswers":["Charlize Theron","Emma Thompson","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Gravity and Speed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bones","incorrectAnswers":["Eyes","Arms","Stomach"],"question":"In what body part does an osteopath specialise?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Owl","incorrectAnswers":["The Robin","The Swan","The Albatross"],"question":"In Edward Lear's poem, which bird sang to the pussycat?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Tempest","incorrectAnswers":["Hamlet","Romeo and Juliet","Macbeth"],"question":"In which play is the Duke of Milan marooned, inspired by the 1609 wreck of an English ship off Bermuda?","difficulty":"medium"},